Florence Deakins Becker Papers
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
Florence Deakins Becker Papers 1891-1963 1910-1963
MSS23523
Becker, Florence Deakins, 1878-1969
3,000 items
10 containers plus 21 oversize
8.2 linear feet
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress Washington, D.C.
Nurse and volunteer worker. Correspondence, diaries, family papers, subject files, speeches and writings, scrapbooks, and other papers relating principally to Becker’s volunteer activities on behalf of various health and medical causes, especially the crusade against tuberculosis and cancer.
Selected Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the LC Catalog. They are grouped by name of person or organization, by subject or location, and by occupation and listed alphabetically.
People
Barron, Clarence W. (Clarence Walker), 1855-1928--Correspondence.; Bartlett, Suzanne Earle Ogden-Jones Emmons, 1861-1954--Correspondence.; Becker, Florence Deakins, 1878-1969.; Becker, George F. (George Ferdinand), 1847-1919--Correspondence.; Bloodgood, Joseph Colt, 1867-1935--Correspondence.; Borah, William Edgar, 1865-1940--Correspondence.; Brown, W. Norman (William Norman), 1892-1975--Correspondence.; Devine, Edward T. (Edward Thomas), 1867-1948--Correspondence.; Dillingham, William P. (William Paul), 1843-1923--Correspondence.; Forrester, John Campbell--Correspondence.; Keen, Florence--Correspondence.; Rush, Thomas E., 1867-1947--Correspondence.; Taft, William H. (William Howard), 1857-1930--Correspondence.
Organizations
American Public Health Association--Correspondence.; George Ferdinand Becker Memorial Library.; Ligue du Nord Contre la Tuberculose.; Michigan Tuberculosis Association.; Tuberculosis Association of Bengal.; Urgent Relief for France.; Washington Animal Rescue League.
Subjects
Animal rescue--Washington (D.C.)--Societies, etc.; Cancer--Prevention.; Health.; Libraries--Virginia--Independence.; Nursing.; Public health--Societies, etc.; Refugees--France.; Tuberculosis--France--Prevention.; Tuberculosis--India--Prevention.; Tuberculosis--Prevention.; Tuberculosis--United States--Prevention.; Veterans' hospitals.; World War, 1914-1918--Medical care.
Places
Maryland--Centennial celebrations, etc.
Occupations
Nurses.; Volunteers.
Acquisition Information
The papers of Florence Deakins Becker, nurse and volunteer worker, were given to the Library of Congrss by her grandniece, Mrs. George F. White, in 1969.
Transfers
Some photographs have been transferred to the Prints and Photographs Division where they are identified as part of the Florence Deakins Becker Papers.
Related Material
Related collections in the Manuscript Division include the papers of her husband, George F. Becker.
Access and Restrictions
The papers of Florence Deakins Becker are open to research. Researchers are advised to contact the Manuscript Reading Room prior to visiting. Many collections are stored off-site and advance notice is needed to retrieve these items for research use.
Biographical Note
Date Event
1878, Nov. 20 Born, Fort Pendleton, Garrett County, Md.
1898 Volunteer hospital worker, Fort Meade, Md., during the Spanish-American War
1902 Married George F. Becker (died 1919)
1903 1917 Member, Board of Managers, Emergency Hospital, Washington, D.C.
1914 Established with nine other women the Grey Ladies, a volunteer organization of the Red Cross
1920 circa 1923 Joined the Rockefeller Anti-Tuberculosis Organization and served as a volunteer in Lille, France
1921 Married John Campbell Forrester (divorced 1930)
1923 Founded the Incorporated Tuberculosis Association and a training school for tuberculosis workers in Bengal, India
1930 circa 1934 Administrator, Joseph Colt Bloodgood's cancer clinic, Baltimore, Md.
1969, Mar. 22 Died, Cambridge, Md.
Scope and Content Note
The papers of Florence Deakins Becker (1878-1969) span the years 1891-1963, with the bulk of the material dating between 1910 and 1963. The papers document her activities as a volunteer worker for several medical causes. Becker devoted her time and energies to combating cancer and tuberculosis. Her papers consist of the following seven series: Diaries, Family Papers, General Correspondence, Speeches and Writings File, Subject File, Miscellany, and Oversize.
The Diaries cover 1924, 1929, and 1944, with some undated entries. Subjects in the diaries and engagement calendars include the Michigan Tuberculosis Association and American efforts to render medical aid to French refugees during World War I.
Most information about Becker's personal life is in the Family Papers. Included is correspondence with various relatives and with her husbands, geologist George F. Becker (died 1919) and John Campbell Forrester, a British national who was a businessman and politician in Scotland and Bengal (India). Following her divorce from Forrester in 1930, Becker resumed her former married name.
The General Correspondence series includes business and personal letters as well as letters exchanged with prominent contemporaries. Business correspondence ranges from the American Public Health Association to professional associates such as Joseph Colt Bloodgood and Thomas E. Rush. Correspondence with friends includes letters exchanged with Clarence W. Barron, Suzanne Bartlett, W. Norman Brown, and Florence Keen. Other correspondents include William Edgar Borah, Edward T. Devine, William P. Dillingham, and William H. Taft.
The Speeches and Writings File provides insight into Florence Becker's extensive work in cancer prevention. Among the most significant material in this series are speeches about protective measures for women against cancer.
Becker was involved in a number of medical organizations, and there is considerable material on these activities in the papers. The Subject File documents her work with the Tuberculosis Association of Bengal, Urgent Relief for France, and the Ligue du Nord Contre la Tuberculose. Becker also studied and reported on medical conditions within veterans' hospitals. Other interests documented in the Subject File include the Maryland tercentenary, her founding of the George Ferdinand Becker Memorial Library in Independence, Virginia, and the Washington Animal Rescue League.
The Miscellany series contains scrapbooks, clippings, miscellaneous printed matter, financial papers, and memorabilia. There are also honors and awards, including La Medaille de la Reconnaissance Lilloise and a citation from the French Committee for Defense Against Tuberculosis.
Arrangement of the Papers
This collection is arranged in seven series:
Diaries, 1924-1944
Family Papers, 1891-1957
General Correspondence, 1902-1962
Speeches and Writings File, 1922-1933
Subject File, 1901-1963
Miscellany, 1891-1954
Oversize, 1903-1929
Container List
- Diaries, 1924-1944 (Box 1)
  Diaries and engagement calendars.
  Arranged chronologically.
  - Diaries, 1924, 1929, 1944, undated (Box 1)
  - Engagement calendars, 1929-1954 (Box 1)
- Family Papers, 1891-1957 (Box 1-2)
  Letters sent and received between family members, including files of Becker's correspondence with her two husbands, biographical information, estate files, memoirs, and printed matter.
  Arranged by name of family member and thereunder chronologically.
  - Bayard, Ora D., 1920-1930 (Box 1)
  - Becker, Conrad, 1921 (Box 1)
  - Becker, George F. (Box 1)
    - Correspondence, 1907-1910 (Box 1)
    - Estate, 1919-1953 (Box 1)
    - Writings, printed matter, and memoirs, 1868-1927 (Box 1)
  - Deakins, Mary L., 1891 (Box 1)
  - Forrester, Isabella, 1921 (Box 1)
  - Forrester, John Campbell (Box 2)
    - Correspondence, 1921-1926, undated, (3 folders) (Box 2)
    - Biographical information, printed matter, writings, and resolutions, 1922-1929 (Box 2)
  - Underwood, Bayard, 1957 (Box 2)
- General Correspondence, 1902-1962 (Box 2-5)
  Letters received, copies of letters sent, and memoranda.
  Arranged alphabetically by correspondent and thereunder chronologically.
  - "A-B" miscellaneous (Box 2)
  - American Archaelogical Society (Box 2)
  - American Public Health Association (Box 2)
  - Ames, Joseph S. (Box 2)
  - Anspacher, Louis K (Box 2)
  - Barnett, Lelia (Box 2)
  - Barron, Clarence W. (Box 3)
  - Bartlett, Suzanne (Box 3)
  - Bidault, Suzanne Borel (Box 3)
  - Bloodgood, Joseph Colt (Box 3)
  - Borah, William E. (Box 3)
  - Brown, Ernest W. (Box 3)
  - Brown, Norman W. (Box 3)
  - "C-E" miscellaneous (Box 3)
  - Carr, Edith K. (Box 3)
  - Davis, William M. (Box 3)
  - Dennis, Alfred (Box 3)
  - Devine, Edward T. (Box 3)
  - De Witt-Guizot, Martha (Box 3)
  - Dillingham, William P. (Box 3)
  - "F-H" miscellaneous (Box 3)
  - Flanagan, Edward J. (Box 4)
  - Flexner, Simon (Box 4)
  - Flournoy, Richard W. (Box 4)
  - Frazer, Robert (Box 4)
  - "G-M" miscellaneous (Box 4)
  - Goldthwait, Joel E. (Box 4)
  - Goto, Baroness Shimpei (Box 4)
  - Jawdat, Ali (Box 4)
  - Keen, Florence (Box 4)
  - Lowell, Abbot L. (Box 4)
  - MacCurdy, George G. (Box 4)
  - Mendehhall, W. C. (Box 4)
  - Mitchell, Harry B. (Box 4)
  - "N-R" miscellaneous (Box 4)
  - Parron, Thomas (Box 4)
  - Pesson-Didion, Viola (Box 4)
  - Reynolds, C. R. (Box 4)
  - Rush, Thomas E., (2 folders) (Box 4)
  - "S-T" miscellaneous (Box 5)
  - Shallow, Michael N. (Box 5)
  - Taft, William H. (Box 5)
  - Tankersley, John F. (Box 5)
  - "U-Z" miscellaneous (Box 5)
  - Vogel, Lilli (Box 5)
  - Walsh, Thomas J. (Box 5)
  - Correspondence of others (Box 5)
  - Unidentified (Box 5)
    - Incoming, (2 folders) (Box 5)
    - Outgoing (Box 5)
- Speeches and Writings File, 1922-1933 (Box 6)
  Speeches, class compositions, literary fragments, and writings by others.
  Arranged alphabetically by title or type of material.
  - "Education of Mothers and Their Doctors in Cancer Prevention" (Box 6)
  - "Knowledge Brings Prevention" (Box 6)
  - "Mothers Should Know" (Box 6)
  - "Prevention and Protection" (Box 6)
  - "Prevention of Cancer of the Cervix through Education of Mothers and Their Doctors" (Box 6)
  - "The Protection of Mothers from Cancer" (Box 6)
  - Untitled speeches (Box 6)
  - Student compositions, 1922 (Box 6)
  - Fragmentary writings (Box 6)
    - By Becker (Box 6)
    - By unidentified author (Box 6)
  - Writings by others (Box 6)
- Subject File, 1901-1963 (Box 6-8)
  Topical files, reports, printed matter, correspondence, photographs, biographical material, and notes.
  Arranged alphabetically by subject or type of material.
  - Bedstead patent (Box 6)
  - Biographical information (Box 6)
  - Cancer (Box 6)
  - Divorce proceedings (Box 7)
  - Founding of library in Independence, Va. (Box 7)
  - Harvey Johnson drowning, legal case (Box 7)
  - Health and medical conditions in veterans' hospitals (Box 7)
  - Maryland tercentenary (Box 7)
  - Tamarack, home of George F. Becker, Stockbridge, Mass. (Box 7)
  - Tuberculosis (Box 7)
    - Correspondence and writings (Box 7)
    - Ligue du Nord contre la Tuberculose (Box 7)
    - Michigan Tuberculosis Association (Box 8)
    - Printed matter (Box 8)
    - Tuberculosis Association of Bengal See also Oversize (Box 8)
  - Urgent Relief for France (Box 8)
  - Washington Animal Rescue League (Box 8)
  - Welfare of the Blind (Box 8)
- Miscellany, 1891-1954 (Box 8-10)
  Financial papers, printed matter, passports, memorabilia, and newspaper clippings.
  Arranged alphabetically by type of material.
  - Financial papers, 1925-1953 (Box 8)
    - Correspondence (Box 8)
    - Investments, (2 folders); (1 folder) (Box 8, Box 9)
  - Holy cards and religious printed matter (Box 9)
  - Honors and awards See also Oversize (Box 9)
  - Lists, autographs, address books, itineraries, and programs (Box 9)
  - Funeral instructions (Box 9)
  - Passport, membership cards, menus, invitations, calling cards, and prescriptions (Box 9)
  - Printed matter (Box 9)
  - Clippings in English, 1911-1954, (4 folders) (Box 10)
  - Clippings and printed matter in French (Box 10)
  - Scrapbooks See Oversize (Box 10)
- Oversize, 1903-1929 (Box OV 1-OV 21)
  Scrapbooks, awards, honors, photographs, and printed matter.
  Arranged and described according to the series, containers, and folder from which the items were removed.
  - Subject File (Box OV 1)
    - Tuberculosis (Box OV 1)
      - Tuberculosis Association of Bengal, photograph 1937 (Container 8) (Box OV 1)
  - Miscellany (Box OV 1)
    - Honors and awards, 1920-1926 (Container 9) (Box OV 1)
  - Miscellany (Box OV 2)
    - Scrapbooks (Box OV 2)
      - Clippings (Box OV 2)
        - 1909, Dec.-1914, Aug. (Box OV 2)
        - 1914, Aug.-Oct. (Box OV 3)
        - 1914, Oct.-1915, Jan. (Box OV 4)
        - 1915 (Box OV 5)
          - Jan.-Mar. (Box OV 5)
          - Mar.-May (Box OV 6)
          - May-Sept. (Box OV 7)
          - Sept.-Dec. (Box OV 8)
        - 1915, Dec.-1916, Mar (Box OV 9)
        - 1916 (Box OV 10)
          - Mar.-June (Box OV 10)
          - June-Sept. (Box OV 11)
          - Sept.-Dec. (Box OV 12)
        - 1917 (Box OV 13)
          - Jan.-Apr. (Box OV 13)
          - Apr.-July (Box OV 14)
          - Aug.-Dec. (Box OV 15)
      - Miscellaneous (Box OV 16)
        - Return address book, 1928-1929 (Box OV 16)
        - Travels in India, Europe, Kashmire, Great Britain, and United States (Box OV 17)
        - Menus, calling cards, and related material, 1903-1911 (Box OV 18)
        - Photographs (Box OV 19)
          - Personal (Box OV 19)
          - India (Box OV 20)
          - Prospective houses (Box OV 21)